<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE teiCorpus SYSTEM "./tei_corpus.dtd">
<teiCorpus>
  <teiHeader>
    <!--File description-->
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <!--Title, author and encoding's responsable-->
        <title>Corpus of reviews</title>
        <author xml:id="auth">
          <persName xml:lang="it">
            <forename>Alessandro </forename>
            <surname>Mazzeo</surname>
          </persName>
        </author>
        <respStmt xml:id="AM">
          <resp>Reviews taken by:</resp>
          <persName>
            <forename>Alessandro</forename>
            <surname>Mazzeo</surname>
          </persName>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <!--Information about editions-->
      <editionStmt>
        <p>1' edition <date>2019</date></p>
      </editionStmt>
      <!--Information about distribution-->
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>Alessandro Mazzeo</distributor>
        <publisher>Alessandro Mazzeo</publisher>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <licence>Creative Commons 4.0 BY SA</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <!--Information about the source where the content is taken-->
      <sourceDesc>
        <p>Born digital</p>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <!--Information about encoding-->
    <encodingDesc>
      <!--Project's purpose-->
      <projectDesc>
        <p> The project is a electronic corpus of reviews about products or services, taken from
          e-commerce and others booking platform. </p>
      </projectDesc>
      <!--Declaration about common encoding editing-->
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Every text element is original.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <!--Not bibliographic description: text language and text typology-->
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>corpus</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="EN">English</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <TEI>
    <!-- Reviews of a product -->
    <teiHeader>
      <!-- Product or service information -->
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>Dell - Inspiron 15.6" Touch-Screen Laptop - Intel Core i3 - 8GB Memory - 128GB SSD
            - Black</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>https://www.bestbuy.com/</distributor>
          <publisher>bestbuy.com</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.S.A.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <!-- One review of the product or service inserted in teiHeader for this element TEI-->
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">BobS</name>
          <title>Perfect for us as an in home email and web viewing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>We were in the market to replace our 12 year old Dell laptop that was getting on in
            years especially limited video capabilities. It came with Vista, was upgraded to W7,
            then W8, then W10. When this new system was Black Friday priced it was a no brainer for
            us. It starts up almost instantly speed tests three times faster the system it replaced.
            Very happy with purchase,</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <!-- Another review of the product or service inserted in teiHeader-->
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">ezek</name>
          <title>Amazing performance for the price</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I got it on an early black friday sale for $279.99, and paying this price for an i3+8GB
            of RAM and the super fast boot up speed of an SSD is the best deal I could've ever
            gotten. Better get it this 2k19 black friday if you are in need of a laptop that gives
            you more than what you pay.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Neuro</name>
          <title>Great Dell quality laptop</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great Dell laptop. The Core i3 makes a difference compared to other entry level chips.
            The 8BG memory and the 128 SSD really helps speed the computer up. Other entry level
            computers typically have 4GB. The touch screen is a bonus, however I rarely use the
            feature. The Ethernet port is nice to have — I see many newer laptops getting rid of
            network ports in favor of being thin or space. Excellent value.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Cstar</name>
          <title>Great for the price</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Nice laptop for a teenager! And good price! Will be a great starter laptop</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">TechGeek56</name>
          <title>Great Computer!! Hate the screen size</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I just purchased this computer today and I'm already liking it. Only thing I don't like
            is the screen size but with the other things it has (128 SSD and 8GB RAM), it's real
            easy to overlook. If you're looking for a good computer under 500.00, this is a really
            good buy!!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">RiGaines</name>
          <title>Good product</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great pc for on base in barracks. It’s light weight for me to carry to/from classes</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Angelsobe</name>
          <title>Dell touch screen</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great computer for great price thanks Best Buy for your service and great price on your
            products</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Spoiling</name>
          <title>Good deal</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Speed is good easy to use and the touch screen is a bonus</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Samy</name>
          <title>Best</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Dell been my favorite for ever and i will be with dell Best computers</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">jtyler</name>
          <title>Highly recommend!</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This is a great laptop for the money, especially when it's on sale for under $300! It
            does have a cheap feel to it but I think that’s an okay trade-off for the price. I found
            the texture of the shell pretty interesting; it’s kind of like a rough plastic which
            adds a good grip feeling for when you have to move it. The keyboard is nice to type on
            and the track pad seems to be good quality. The in-line power brick is a nice compact
            size which, to me, is a big plus. This Inspiron is also very thin considering the price,
            and it's surprisingly lightweight. I was also pleased with the SD card slot included on
            the side. I found the performance to be really good if you're just watching YouTube or
            browsing the web. The 8th gen Intel i3 processor and 8GB of RAM is great for
            low-demanding tasks similar to those. Playing 4K video on YouTube runs without a hitch
            while only utilizing about 30% of the integrated Intel UHD Graphics 620 GPU. This would
            be a great budget laptop for school or even work depending on what you do. I'm sure it
            could run Microsoft Word or Excel without any problems. I was surprise at the lack of
            bloatware that was preinstalled. Like other reviewers have noted, I did have to go
            through the activation troubleshooter to activate the "home" version of Windows 10 to
            change out of the Windows 10 S mode. One thing that bugs me about this laptop is the
            lack of backlit keys. The screen displays a decent picture but I can still tell it’s a
            lower resolution. I think 1920x1080 is the sweet spot for a 15 inch screen. The screen
            also has a glossy finish which creates a lot of screen glare, especially in a bright
            environment. It also lacks a removable battery which is a con for me; I like to remove
            the battery when I know I'm going to leave it in one spot for a while. I would
            definitely recommend this over any Chromebook though. Sure, there are better Windows
            laptops out there but this one is hard to beat for the price!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">HardingN88</name>
          <title>Great laptop</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Screen is very responsive, doesn't lag during normal operation, battery life is great.
            Bought for my daughter for school and couldn't be more pleased.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Ironpump89</name>
          <title>For the price it costs it is a decent laptop</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Pretty capable laptop. Touch screen is a plus and display feels good overall
            quality</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Ariel</name>
          <title>Good laptop for the price</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>So far no issues, fast and it had a very good price tag.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Prashi</name>
          <title>Excellent configuration for the price</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Bought this on early black friday deal. Great configuration for the offer price.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Ozmaster</name>
          <title>Good value</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Surprisingly fast overall. Fast boot-up. Surprisingly not filled with junk. Screen
            resolution too low for text to look decent. Still good for the price.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">shashi</name>
          <title>Always like Dell</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Best for casual browsing and beginner and best value.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>Ad Astra BD [Blu-ray] [2019]</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>https://www.amazon.co.uk</distributor>
          <publisher>amazon</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">The Movie Diorama</name>
          <title>Ad Astra galactically depicts sorrow, proving that no one can hear you cry in
            space. </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Ad Astra galactically depicts sorrow, proving that no one can hear you cry in space.
            For the past few years, dramas set in the expansive dangers of space have been my bread
            and butter. Devouring them during my annual breakfast as I purposefully starve myself
            for the taste of space traversal. Every year, the likes 'Arrival', 'Blade Runner 2049',
            'First Man', 'Interstellar' and my all-time favourite film 'Gravity', have secured
            scores ranging from outstanding to perfect. Whilst Ad Astra may be tilting towards the
            former adjective, it's still irrefutably one of the best films of the year thanks to
            Gray's understanding, yet again, of what makes a character study captivating. After
            unearthing the possibility that his missing father may still be alive, his astronaut son
            travels across the Solar System in search for him and to unravel a mysterious power
            surge phenomenon that threatens humanity's survival. Immediately, one thing I need to
            brush off my chest is the horrendous marketing. This is not a sci-fi blockbuster. There
            is limited "action". And if you're wanting the next 'Star Wars' or 'Avatar', then remove
            yourself from the cinema and watch mind-numbing nonsense like 'Angel Has Fallen'
            instead. This is a James Gray extravaganza. A meticulously woven character study,
            harnessing melancholia to challenge an existential crisis. Thematically, Ad Astra's
            premise bolsters a plethora of metaphorical imagery that divulges into the empirical
            purpose of humanity. Majestic planets emitting every prismatic shade available, yet
            emanating no emotional connectivity. The vacuous expansivity of space, marking
            humanity's reflection on life as a mere speck of stardust. Worldly hostility reaching
            the depths of our galaxy, hyperbolising the "world-eating" philosophy of our own
            self-destruction as a species. The obsession to venture forth. Departing love, hate and
            grief. Welcoming nothingness. Gray's space-opera is a sorrowful tale, intently focusing
            on the pressures of a son following in the footsteps of his acclaimed father. A
            patriarch of inspiration to many. Allowing a tangible tense bond to illuminate the stars
            with despair and anguish. Pitt's universally nuanced performance brings forward stoic
            mannerisms that allow McBride to feel these emotions. Minor glitches that break
            character, such as slamming the wall in frustration, showcase the purity of humanity
            within him. Gray encompasses the plot around McBride. The lunar pirate raid, mayday
            rescue and crew brawl scenes, whilst inserting mainstream tendencies into a contemporary
            drama, were emblems of McBride's emotions. Fear, rage and desperation respectively. A
            series of gestures that, again, hark back to humanity's endurance. The mildly engaging
            supporting cast, ranging from Jones, Sutherland and Negga, acting as stability for
            McBride. Stepping stones allowing him to find his father, as if fate was dictating his
            alignment. Narration, shifting between inner thoughts to exposition, was overused and
            irked me with its basic functionality. Hoytema's cinematography could've elicited these
            unnecessary lines of dialogue from his beautiful imagery. And beautiful just doesn't do
            it justice. Immediately, from the iridescent opening shot, Hoytema takes hold. Utilising
            colours and shadows to produce the incarnation of life, what it means to see. The blue
            of Neptune, the red of Mars. Clashing tonalities resembling McBride's emotions.
            Accompanied by Richter's euphoric score and the almost '2001' production design, and Ad
            Astra is technically a masterful piece of art. Gray's conclusion is teetering on the
            edge of underwhelming, for me atleast, with its rushed journey home that dissipated the
            simmering sorrow built exquisitely beforehand. The ending I personally would've desired,
            would be the ending no one wanted (but that's life I guess...). Regardless, the small
            criticisms here and there are subject to change upon an inevitable rewatch. Gray is fast
            becoming one of my favourite directors. He is a man who understands character. He
            acknowledges the obsession of man. Amalgamating life's wondrously challenging hurdles
            into singular expressive characters. Ad Astra's meditative and resonant pacing, whilst
            is sure to put many viewers off, ensures that loss and grief are captured wherever a
            soul may be. At home or in deep space. It never vanishes. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Rowena Hoseason</name>
          <title>Intelligent life in outer space </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>AD ASTRA isn’t space fantasy or the wild west in orbit. It’s proper science fiction,
            more like 2001 than Star Wars. We enjoyed it waaaaay more than First Man, Interstellar
            or Gravity – perhaps because Brad Pitt’s brilliant performance is so perfectly
            controlled, not muted or subdued, but as if all the emotional intensity is being
            condensed within him… until it reaches critical mass. And the action sequences are
            simply superb. Many movie car chases / fight scenes / set pieces tend to feel completely
            unreal these days, thanks to ubiquitous CGI tweaking. It’s ironic, then, that the
            completely unreal scenarios in Ad Astra, which involve space-walks and rockets firing
            and lunar buggies, are completely convincing. It takes a lot to raise my pulse during a
            film but I was utterly transfixed. And touched, too, by the protagonist’s philosophical
            progress; his unresolved relationship with his father underpinning his (failing)
            relationships with everyone else. All the supporting stars deserve applause for their
            contributions – often oblique, almost out of sight, but massive in impact. I even
            forgive the occasionally wobby science (because hey, it’s only a film). 9/10 </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Ratty</name>
          <title>The search for intelligent life? </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The search for intelligent life; not in outer space but in the writers of the plot
            line. I guest; however the plot line is somewhat simplistic and far fetched in parts.
            I'd read critics are comparing it to '2001 A Space Odyssey '. Well I was sorely
            disappointed in that. It's about as close to 2001 as The Lion King is to Hamlet. No with
            2001 you're asking your self, all the way through what's all this means and afterwards
            fans can discuss what each element signifide. Where as this is what you see. The story
            is laid unambiguously out for you to easily follow. Brad Pitt's character (Roy McBride)
            has lived his life as a astronaut who's, otherwise, glittering carrier as been
            constantly eclipsed by the shadow of his fathers legendary carrier. His father
            disappeared on the first and only deep space mission to the out reaches of the solar
            system in the hope of finding evidence of extra terrestrial intelligent life some
            sixteen years earlier. At the time of the movie Earth is hit by power surges that cause
            power blackouts over the entire globe. On an analysis it is determined that these power
            surges are bursts of antimatter and that if they continue they will eventually destroy
            all life in the solar-system. They trace their origins to Neptune and realise that's
            where McBride's dad was last known to have been before he disappeared and not only that
            his spacecraft was powered by the only antimatter generator ever built. Two plus Two
            equals McBride's dad is coursing the power surges. Roy McBride is sumound to travel to
            Mars and there broadcast a signal to his dad in the hope of stopping the surges. McBride
            broadcasts the message but goes off script and sends his own message, this gets him
            taken off the mission so he goes rouge and hi jacks the spacecraft now being sent to
            destroy his dad's craft. All very simplistic and comic book and a lot of the action
            relies to much on exceptional convenience rather than timing and skill. You know the
            thing just when all is lost, there is the one thing he needs to save the situation, once
            is good fortune, twice stretching it but every time he trusts to luck it comes through
            for him; at that rate he'd win the lottery every week. And successfully braking into a
            rocket, on the launch pad, while the rockets are igniting and then accidently killing
            the crew of three with three different accidents in the space of thirty seconds is hard
            to take. Kill one in the struggle, hurt another, maybe or even kill all three with one
            action but to set of a chain of events that takes out all three in different ways; a
            somewhat convenient way for the writers to dispose of them. Not to mention all the other
            amassing things he pulls off in space, jumping twice the length of a football pitch and
            hitting his target, a six inch hand hold, every time, surfing Neptune's rings on a metal
            plate he unscrewed from one spacecraft to get to another spacecraft miles away the other
            side of Neptune's rings. All captain fantastic comic book for what is supposed to be an
            intelligent narrative. As a bit of escapes entertainment it passes the time. Actings a
            bit ham dram, direction a bit obvious. Special effects not that good. Moon Rover car
            chase, they forgot, or hoped we'd forgotten, there's only one sixth gravity on the moon.
            The rovers manoeuvre and behaved just as they would on earth and not as they would on
            the moon. Other things also didn't behave as they would in space. Also I was getting
            tired of seeing American Flags everywhere. They mention other nations on the moon and in
            space but showed no flags other than American ones and they are on everything, space
            craft, buildings, uniforms, equipement, vehicles, memorial plaques you name it and it's
            got an American Flag on it. In all entertaining but very little else to commend it. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Massey</name>
          <title>Worst Film Of 2019 </title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>SWatched this at the cinema and I couldn't stop comparing it to another crappy film
            called gravity An astronaut gets sent to space to uncover a mission that happened years
            ago to trace the commanding officer of another spaceship doing a top secret mission for
            the government Along the way discoveries are made that it was a cover up and the
            conspiracy theory is that something or someone is still alive on the other spaceship and
            whatever is happening threatens all life on earth That is not a spolier at all it goes
            deeper than that if you can get though watching the piece of crap It was so draining to
            watch my friend actually fell asleep that's a first Save your money do not buy or see
            this film </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">TJ Ramsbottom</name>
          <title>Half a masterpiece </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>A tale of two halves, this one. The first 60 minutes or so have some of the best sci-fi
            moments in recent years, right up there with First Man or Interstellar. The tone is very
            much Terence Mallick in space; thoughtful narration over deceptively day-to-day
            activities for astronaut Brad Pitt. The cinematography and sound design and effects are
            all top notch. Pitt has done the stoic manly man role before and it would have been easy
            to repeat himself but his character is far more buttoned up here than usual and Pitt
            never takes the obvious route. Outstanding sequences include a pirate attack on the moon
            (genuinely something you haven't seen before) and a traumatic (but rather unnecessary)
            detour to visit an animal research vessel. But around the halfway point is where things
            start to slip a little. Pitt goes looking for his crazy dad on Neptune and the film
            increasingly resorts to cliche or is simply illogical. There was a five minute period
            where I literally had no idea what was going or why. The answers are not as profound as
            the filmmakers seem to think and I walked out the cinema frustrated at how blandly the
            story concluded (the less said about Liv Tyler's wafer thin role, the better). So a
            mixed bag, but the first half is near perfect which only makes the second half all the
            more disappointing. It doesn't ruin it outright but it stops it becoming the masterpiece
            it could have been. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mr. R. W. Graham</name>
          <title>Signs Of Life </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>In the near future, astronaut Roy McBride goes in search of his father, a famous
            astronaut missing and until recently presumed dead. Slow but intelligent and compelling
            scifi drama with Brad Pitt giving one of his best performances and with good support
            from Tommy Lee Jones, Donald Sutherland and Ruth Negga. It's an intelligent look at what
            space travel in the future will likely be like, dealing with isolation and loneliness
            plus huge distances. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mr. M. A. Crown</name>
          <title>Promises Much But Does Not Deliver </title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I saw this at the cinema. Firstly, the cinematography is amazing - visually it is
            stunning to look at. However, other than that it rapidly goes down hill. This film
            borrows from other better, films. The journey Pitt's character takes to rendezvous with
            his father is rather like that of 2001 A Space Odyssey and Heart of Darkness combined
            (Apocalypse Now). The incessant psycho testing Pitt's character endures is rather like
            that seen in Bladerunner 2045 performed on the principal character. The tension builds
            with what looks like a father and son reunion and reckoning and then...………….nothing.
            Whatever is settled when the two men meet is never really explored or made clear. The
            internal emotional life of Pitt's character is never really revealed or contrasted with
            that of his father. Motivations are not clear. I left the theatre feeling rather short
            changed. There was some sort of resolution in the story but it was muffled and
            incoherent to me. There have been a lot of excellent sci-fi films of late (Interstellar,
            Bladerunner 2045, Arrival, even Oblivion and the Alien franchise). But I'm afraid that
            Ad Astra is not one of them by a long margin. Pitt and Tommy Lee Jones are better than
            this. Besides the sumptuous technical appearance, this film is just a thematic void when
            compared to the deep space it depicts. Avoid. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Jack Ransom</name>
          <title>Ad Astra </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This film really scratched an itch I’d had for a while with sci-fi films probably since
            ‘Blade Runner 2049’ a couple of years ago and is far more interesting and different then
            its trailers would have you believe. ‘Ad Astra’ follows astronaut Roy McBride (Brad
            Pitt) undertakes a mission across space to uncover the truth about his missing father
            (Tommy Lee Jones) and his doomed expedition which now, 30 years later threatens the
            universe. This is probably the most visually impressive film I have seen this year when
            it comes it’s locations and cinematography. From the moment the thrilling and incredibly
            realistic opening sequence of Pitt’s character falling through the sky from space
            happened I knew that I was in for a treat with the technical aspects. The space scenes
            and planets are epic to see (I would definitely recommend this for an IMAX viewing), the
            interiors of the ships gave me a very ‘2001: A Space Odyssey’ feel, especially with some
            excellent use of a red colour palette later in the film. However my favourite shots have
            to be the sections where the light bounces off the astronaut suit helmets and when we
            see distorted and/or curved reflections of the character’s surroundings, a really unique
            technique. I also liked the world building, with it being in the near future humans have
            now migrated to the Moon, Jupiter etc. and we see various franchise outlets, living
            situations etc. which I appreciated. The score of the film is also haunting and epic
            throughout when it occurs, as a lot of the film is very quiet or with Pitt’s narration,
            which makes the score even more impactful when you hear it. ‘Ad Astra’ nails being epic
            in scope with its story themes as well as being a very personal and focused character
            study of a man dealing with father issues and how we will come to face and overcome
            them. Pitt has had a great year this year, this role of Roy McBride is a complete
            contrast from the cool and upbeat attitude of ‘Once Upon A Time... In Hollywood’s’ Cliff
            Booth. McBride is somber, quiet and only focuses on his job. Pitt has a lot of time by
            himself in this film and a lot of his emotion is conveyed through facial expressions
            rather than dialogue, combining the two aspects make for some really great and emotional
            dramatic scenes (especially where he is trying to contact his father and the finale
            sequence which I won’t spoil). It’s also good to see Tommy Lee Jones on the big screen
            again in a good role here as the distant and obsessive father McBride, his screentime is
            fairly limited but Jones steals the screen when he’s in any scene. ‘Ad Astra’ is a slow
            burn film and some people will be expecting a different film to what the trailers have
            led them to believe, with the marketing pushing a more action heavy film. There are some
            impressive action sequences, the Moon driving shootout sequence is thrilling and there’s
            a couple of intense and bloody fights (one of which I was completely unexpecting with a
            very sci-fi horror tone to it). But aside from those it is very dialogue heavy and with
            long camera takes. The more I think about it and whilst writing this review the more I
            really appreciated and loved ‘Ad Astra’. It’s a blend of ‘Apocalypse Now’ (yes that’s
            right) with its ‘quest for important person’ character study plot but set within ‘2001:
            A Space Odyssey’s’ world. It’s a bold and original sci-fi adventure with brilliant
            performances and excellent cinematography and writing, that will give you a lot to think
            about and demands repeat viewing. One of my favourites of this year, highly
            recommend.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Diggy</name>
          <title>Rubbish, really total rubbish </title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Possibly the worst science fiction film of all time. There's no understanding of
            science and the fiction is a sucession of half plots with little rhyme, reason or
            conclusion. It lost me at (spoiler alert) the attack of the Norwegian cannibal space
            monkeys - I kid you not. Do anything with your precious 2 hours than watch this tosh.
          </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Gordon C. Tait</name>
          <title>Symbolism and poetry - sadly missed by most. </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>For all those who are critiquing the movie's flawed science, and focus purely on that,
            then you have missed a very poignant effort from Brad Pitt and Co. The film focuses on
            astronaut Roy McBride who has been "volunteered" to embark on a mission to contact his
            father who commandeered a failed mission to Neptune in the hope of finding alien life.
            After a series of surges that have plagued Earth, the Government fears that McBride's
            father may be responsible and deploy his son in the hope of terminating his command.
            That's the premise but not the real story. Within the grandiose interplanetary
            photography and stunning production design, McBride's journey takes him on a journey of
            self-relisation and alienation - the central theme of the movie. With almost every shot,
            we are subtly given insight into Brad Pitt's troubled character and journey which he
            plays to perfection. Yes, you may have found parallels with Apocalypse Now and that is
            true, but this is not a cheap imitation. The poetry of the movie if represented by the
            celestial bodies, planets, and the distance between them which serves as a mirror for
            McBride's lonliness and alienation from the people in his life. For a pleasant change, a
            film is asking more of the viewer than the average theme-park-ride movies of late. If
            you are looking for a science adventure epic, then this is not for you. That said, one
            cannot ignore the mind-blowing visuals, in particular, the moon chase and the final
            scene orbiting Neptune. If however, you are looking for a slow burner that appeals to
            the more discerning viewer that can interpret the director's subtle realisation and
            visual cues instead of mocking the physics, you are in for a treat. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Barry Wom</name>
          <title>Not as smart as it thinks it is. </title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Love me a bit of slow burning philosophical sci-fi. We’ve had some interesting films in
            the last decade. Also like me a good character drama set against the back drop of space
            exploration. Sometimes you get a bit of both and Ad Astra, on the surface and having
            already been warned that the trailers were somewhat misleading, appeared to be offering
            something thoughtful. To me it fell short by some distance and came across as long
            winded, for its average running time, a bit pretentious and clunky. The oedipal come
            existential message isn’t as subtle as it thinks yet at the same time manages to find
            itself truncated by a silly ending and some odd creative choices. The studio mandated
            action scenes just seemed out of place and non consequential adding nothing to the
            narrative and little to the theme. The moon segment looks like it was stolen directly
            from Episode 2 of ‘Futurama’ and much of the rest of the film from the disjointed ‘Event
            Horizon’, from way back, although it’s obviously trying to ape ‘Apocalypse Now’. Can’t
            fault the lovely photography and good effects. Brad gives a good turn. Tommy is in it
            briefly and is underwhelming. Other stars come and disappear abruptly and one, in
            particular, has absolutely nothing to do. It’s not awful but given some obvious love
            that’s gone into it is very disappointing and certainly no masterpiece. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Moira</name>
          <title>O Father, Where Art Thou? </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Generally more psychological than action driven, the plot of Ad Astra has a measured
            pace which allows the main character, Roy, to reflect on the personal and environmental
            downside of space exploration. In adolescence, he lost his astronaut father, H.
            Clifford, to an expedition, searching for extra terrestrial life. This has closed Roy
            down emotionally while focussing his energies on becoming an astronaut too. He readily
            accepts an assignment to try to track down his father, who it is believed, may still be
            out there and responsible for power surges emanating from Neptune which threaten Earth.
            En route, this allows Roy to show and describe, how the commercial side of space travel
            has already led to the Disneyfication of the Moon and is spreading wherever colonisation
            goes. Action scenes along the way vary the pace of the film. At their best they are well
            executed visually with curved reflections that create a sense of claustrophobia while
            wider shots are scarily vertiginous. At their worst, however, they stray from the film's
            own logic, sucking the plot into little black holes of implausibility, including some
            gory 'monkey business' and an unlikely stowaway caper. Thoughtful, but probably not as
            profound as it imagines. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mr. R. Stanton</name>
          <title>Brad Pitt vs the space monkeys </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Roy McBride is a well respected astronaut who is sent on a top secret mission to the
            outer edges of the Solar System to retrieve his father who he believed had died many
            years earlier when they lost contact with his crew. He is also asked to investigate the
            strange pulse signals known as the surge that have caused devastation upon Earth and
            many believe they have originated from the same place as the last known location of
            McBride's father. Technically, Ad Astra is a superb film and it looks stunning. It's a
            difficult one to describe or to even say whether I enjoyed or not. I think it is one of
            those films that needs to be seen more than once. If Terence Malick made a film set in
            space this would be it. He is a big fan of the internal existential monologues and they
            are here in abundance. There are also influences from Apocalypse Now / Heart of Darkness
            and some of the more visceral thrills from the likes of Gravity. Lite on the action, big
            on the thinking, it's worth watching if you have the patience, not so much if you're a
            fan of aliens and shoot-outs. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mark Dyer</name>
          <title>2001 : Apollo-colypse Now </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>As a simple piece of entertainment it's not bad or quite good, possibly about 20
            minutes too long but that is very debateable. Good cinematography, sound, images and I
            liked much of Brad's work in extreme close-up. However, in much the same way that going
            fishing is not about going fishing this is a space film that's not about space. There is
            too much that seems to have been lifted from Apocalypse Now, including the intrusive
            voice-over and the music was overbearing. I enjoyed the spectacle of the set-piece
            scenes and they were put together well but they seem to have been dropped into the story
            just to spice up the film; I suppose without them the 'journey' would have been almost
            pure 2001 rather than just similar to that. The final scenes were quite weak in my
            opinion and the final piece to camera so unsubtle that it's as if the previous hour or
            so of voiceovers hadn't happened. A reasonable way of spending a couple of hours but
            nothing exceptional, which was a bit of a disappointment because I wanted it to be good.
          </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>Places in the Darkness byChris Brookmyre</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>https://www.amazon.co.uk</distributor>
          <publisher>amazon</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">P. G. Harris</name>
          <title>Do Androids Dine on Electric Neeps? </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Or Philip K Dick writes an Angelique de Xavier novel Or Glasgow in space Places in the
            Darkness opens in a very dark place, with two workers on a space station discovering a
            spectacularly dismembered corpse. The story then switches to an Arthur C Clarke style
            space elevator, bringing a new head of security, Dr Alice Blake, to the space station
            Ciudad de Cielo. On the way she is having trouble with her memory. The City in the Sky,
            overseen by the Federation of National Governments, and by a consortium of
            multinationals is humankind's hope for a gateway to the universe. The scientific and
            psychological research is underway to enable interstellar missions to be launched. The
            picture transmitted back to earth is of a utopian, crimeless society. The reality on the
            floors of the rotating space station is very different. "Detective" Nicole Freeman aka
            Nikki Fixx is a corrupt cop, working in the vice dens on one of the city's two wheels.
            When Alice is warned about Nikki by a self righteous campaigner, she sets out to find
            out about the places of darkness hidden behind the facade. This leads to a classic chalk
            and cheese relationship between rookie and gumshoe, between idealistically pure, and
            pragmatically dirty, between posh and streetwise. As the killings start to mount, Alice
            and Nikki are drawn deeper into the greater and more dangerous secrets which lie at the
            heart of their world. While this is very much a piece of hard science fiction, well
            rooted in the classics of the genre, with the halfway station on the space elevator
            being called Heinlein, it is also recognisably a Christopher Brookmyre crime novel. The
            gruesome killings, the gangsters, the very slightly over the top plot could have come
            straight out of a Jack Parlabane book. Places in the Darkness also fits neatly into the
            tradition of Philip K Dick. It uses science fiction, and specifically robotics and
            artificial intelligence to explore the question of what it is to be human. It also
            challenges the concept of utopia, setting out its manifesto that not only will any
            utopia be brought down by human nature, but that the places of darkness within our souls
            are a necessary part of being human. Another aspect of the book which is characteristic
            of Brookmyre is that it is a cracking good read, pacy, intricately plotted, and
            massively entertaining. All the way through, Brookmyre works hard to telegraph the
            approaching twist in the tale, but of course, when it comes it goes in a different
            direction from the false trail he has laid. I would make two specific negative comments.
            Firstly, the ending is a little too neat, a little too redemptive, although Brookmyre
            writes with his heart so obviously in the right place he almost gets away with it.
            Secondly, if you have an inner geek, you are likely to be upset by the occasional
            technical howlers, for example, a massive structure, rotating in zero gravity cant just
            stop. All in all, this will probably work for regular readers of both SF and crime
            fiction, and so if you enjoyed Alastair Reynolds' "The Prefect", this is likely to be to
            your taste. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">pjh</name>
          <title>Not the usual Brookmyre standard </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I am a huge Chris Brookmyre fan. I don’t think this is one of his best. Unlike his
            non-sci-fi novels, which usually have pacy plots and witty dialogue, this book seemed to
            spend too long focussing on describing what the author was predicting could happen in
            the future, detracting from the plot. I usually have a “give up after the first 50
            pages” approach if I don’t get on with a book, and I wanted to do this here but
            persevered because it was Brookmyre, and it did get better, but never reached the old
            standard for me. Maybe I’m just not a sci-fi fan. Can we go back to 21st century Earth
            for the next one Chris? </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mrs Lou M Bell</name>
          <title>It's Brookmyre, Jim, but not as we know him... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>If you're expecting the near-the-knuckle wisecracks and biting satire of the Parlabane
            years, this is probably not for you. If you liked Bedlam, or even Pandaemonium (which
            could be described as his crossover to SF if you like pigeonholing things), then you're
            nearer the mark. I'm a glutton for anything the man writes, and am also a bit of a
            Sci-Fi fan (okay, a lot. Okay, I'm a total geek), so I loved it. The space station idea
            is a good one - it gives a nice sense of claustrophobia, and also means it's not too
            broad a canvas so that Mr B can do what he does best - strong plot and characterisation.
            I'm not a scientist so am unable to pick holes in his physics (though I'm aware holes
            are there to be picked if that's what floats your boat). It's basically a detective
            novel in space with a nice SF twist (which I kind of saw coming but as I said, I'm a fan
            of the genre - as is Chris Brookmyre, clearly). Guessing the twist didn't make the
            experience any less enjoyable IMO. You just switch from 'where's he going with this?' to
            'how's he going to get us there?'. He rarely disappoints. His main characters here are
            initially not easy to like, but what Brookmyre is expert at is tilting the narrative so
            that we end up sympathising with them both, for different reasons (see also
            Pandaemonium, which does this a few times). There's clear potential for more along these
            lines, and I for one definitely be reading it. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Dunfermline woman</name>
          <title>Fast paced believable sci fi. Hard to put down. </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I was delighted to see Chris Brookmyre had published another book whilst I wasn't
            looking and having struggled through an overlong book with lots of discussion and not
            much action enjoyed having a fast paced book I struggled to put down again. It's sci fi
            but believable sci fi. The plot twists and turns but is never far fetched. It makes you
            think about the potential ramifications of a lot of the tech we're currently developing.
            Some of the discussion around the brain deciding what it's going to do before we think
            up reasons why we're doing it, and many of these reasons being just tales we tell
            ourselves to try and create a logical narrative are current not future science, as I
            presume the author knows to make his future seem more plausible It all ties up nicely
            too, too many authors just seem to stop writing and struggle to end their stories. Good
            to see flawed women as central characters. If you want to immerse yourself in another
            reality for a few hours read this. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Cubeist</name>
          <title>Too superficial and needy </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The good points; it's well written from an action point of view, the pace is good. As a
            general thriller it works well. If you let it wash over you it works, as long as you
            don't think too much about sciency stuff and the social commentary (which the author
            probably does want you to). The bad points; the sci-fi is superficial, there's nothing
            new or groundbreaking. The whole idea of what it is to be human has been done better in
            other sci-fi books. If you're crossing over into the genre because of the author's past
            work then ok, but anyone coming to as a sci-fi lover won't find much to think about.
            Then there's the needy bit, the identity-politics stuff was clunky. Nearly all the major
            characters are female, and you're repeatedly told how much tougher they are than the men
            around them. There were several relationships, sexual or otherwise, all of them were
            homosexual. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Lindsey</name>
          <title>I am also an enormous fan of Science Fiction and was delighted to find one of my
            favourite authors venturing into ... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I am a big fan of Christopher Brookmyre, after discovering Quite Ugly One Morning a
            long time ago. So many things chimed with my own life experience it eventually got a
            little creepy - I used to live in the same street as Jack Parlabane - however... I am
            also an enormous fan of Science Fiction and was delighted to find one of my favourite
            authors venturing into space. Gritty and real space at that, with malt whisky. This is
            not the Utopian dream of Star Trek, nor galaxy-spanning space battles. It's a story
            about humanity, and thus is accessible for the non Sci Fi orientated. As always a well
            crafted story exploring interesting themes, and very readable. Nice one Mr Brookmyre,
            I'd be happy to read more of the same. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">David Hartlebury</name>
          <title>Are we who we think we are? </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This is an interesting murder mystery, if also science fiction. You are about to become
            chief of the police and have been told there is corruption in the force. The publicity
            for the place of your new job is there are no murders here. The first thing to happen is
            you wake up half way there to the sound of children's voices, but there are not to be
            children there. However, these are children of a rich supporter of the projects in your
            new home. The next thing to happen is you cannot remember anything of what happened
            before you went to sleep and you are confronted with a vicious murder. You are told that
            the person helping you is corrupt. The story spreads on from there. Nothing is truly
            what it seems! This is an interesting story. The baddies are not the truly bad people.
            It is interesting that everyone believes that their minds are incorruptible when it is
            shown this is not so! The point of the story is what people will do in the name of
            progress and "for the good of the people". I am sure that this is a get out for all who
            do things bad to people to salve their conscience! Good story and maybe there can be a
            follow up as the ending leaves a way to other actions following on. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Malcolm R</name>
          <title>Neither fish nor foul but good </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Whodunnit in space. Sci-Fi police adventure. Cursory rumination on consciousness, AI,
            memory and being human/Android. All of these and thus a bit too much goes on though not
            too much in the way of thrills, detection or mystery. The story is nicely told, the
            culprit obvious but with a fair twist at the end though the plot is hampered by too much
            explanation of the environs where a sci-if writer would simply make it space opera and
            use the space station as scenery. Isaac Asimov dabbled with crime in space in “The Caves
            of Steel” and “The Naked Sun”, Daneel is a much better android copper! My overall
            feeling is that it is very enjoyable but I was left with a niggling dissatisfaction and
            I’m not sure why. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Jac-in-the-book</name>
          <title>Well done, Mr Brookmyre! </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This is my first foray into Chris Brookmyre's sci-fi and I'm so glad I gave it a go.
            The ideas, the characterisation and the writing are first class and as well as that we
            get a piercing light shone on our likely future political/business culture which sadly
            demonstrates many of the same faults as it does now. Despite this, decency and humanity
            are still to be found which leaves a sense of optimism at the end of a page-turning
            plot. Highly recommended. More please! </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Fjb</name>
          <title>AGood sci-fi-detective story </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>A change in direction for the author not direct am convinced by the change I love
            Brookmyre's work one fine day in the Middleton the night was his first book I read it
            was/is brilliant. I have read all his other books this one has many of same themes a
            flawed but fundamentally decent main protagonists decent. Examinations of power and
            corruption. If he writes another in the same,world with Nikki Freeman I'll give it a go
            but remain to be convinced </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Kindle Customer</name>
          <title>Bit Different </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Been a Christopher Brookmyre fan for quite some time. Got this to see what he'd be like
            without all the bits that attracted me in the first place. You know, the Scottishness,
            the dark humour and looking for the title of the next book. Not a great sci fi fan but I
            really enjoyed this book, he really does write well. On the negative side it's not the
            most original sci fi ever. Can't go into that much, too many spoilers but there's a lot
            of P K Dick in there. A good fun read, hope he writes more. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Keen Reader</name>
          <title>Not for me... too much Basil Exposition </title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I normally love Chris Brookmyre books, but I'm about 34% in with this one and can't be
            doing with it any more. I don't feel anything for the characters, have no idea who
            anyone is because they're all painted so thinly and there's too much of a starring role
            for Basil Exposition. Sad to say but I'm giving up. Life is finite, as is my
            patience.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Brian Allan</name>
          <title>Lacks punch </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Places in the Darkness follows a pair of mismatched police officers on a space station.
            It felt to me that it took a while to find its feet and it was a bathe to each the half
            way point, at which point it improved. My main complaint is it felt like the author was
            pulling his punches. The chaotic humour of his early books is missing, barring a few
            tantalising glimpses. The book would have been far better for it. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Number 6</name>
          <title>Space, Plot, Characters and Tension </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Brookmyre moves into orbit with a plot high on tension and character. He paints as PME
            graphic images and does ahis usual job in building an intricate story that keeps you
            hooked. Not much of the early Christopher Brookmyre humour but still quite a smattering
            of the sarcasm and tension he has adopted as Chris. A very readable novel for both
            Sci-Fi buffs and Parlabane readers, although with Alice taking over as the hero(ine).
          </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">NQureshi</name>
          <title>Blade Runner in space... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This was a classic piece of space noir which rocketed along with stellar urgency, the
            page-turning tempo belies some of the novel's weighty themes (memory, identity, what it
            means to be human). It is by no means derivative of great sci fi noir Blade Runner but
            tackles some of the same territory, albeit in a setting and style that is all
            Brookmyre's. The characterisation of the two lead characters is compelling and authentic
            and - as is the author's forte - the pages zing with some cracking one-liners and
            dialogue. A superb novel. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">grumpyhead</name>
          <title>Much ado about nothing </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Not really sure what to write about this book...I had high hopes for it but alas they
            were unfulfilled. Not a great deal happens in the book story wise; I couldn't emphasise
            with any of the characters and the sci-fi was lo-fi. It was one of those books that is
            ok in places but I really just wanted to get it finished to get started on something
            more entertaining </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">R. Norton</name>
          <title>Places in The Darkness doesn't disappoint </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I've been a big fan of Christopher Brookmyre's work for years, he's one of my "go to"
            authors but several chapters in and I was worried that he'd lost his touch. I shouldn't
            have doubted him. The characters, plot twists and vivid descriptions of the space
            station and it's rotten underbelly gradually reeled me in. Don't have any doubts, buy
            this book, you won't be disappointed. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">S. Hayes</name>
          <title>I nearly gave it 6 </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I thought the writing here was utterly fantastic. Definitely a solid 6. The story was
            very decent SF cum whodunnit with a Film Noir atmosphere like Chinatown (Jack Nicholson,
            Faye Dunaway). A definite pageturner. I am now following this author The ending wrapped
            everything up, just that I didn't like it, so a mere 5 </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Malcolm Risk </name>
          <title>Meet the Space Race... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Brookmyre takes all his earthbound gifts of humour, characterisation, social commentary
            and good, old-fashioned story telling, and elegantly transfers them off-planet for a
            sci-fi murder mystery with bells on. It’s a sort of Brave New World meets The Handmaid’s
            Tale meets Blade Runner meets Frankenstein morality tale with the usual mix of witty
            dialogue, sharp plot twists and thought-provoking context. Buy it. Read it. Love it.
          </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Craig McGill</name>
          <title>Good but... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>It’s not a bad book but it takes a long time to get going. Without going into spoilers,
            once the main storyline reveals itself everything gets better but it just takes a long,
            long time to get there (as in Act III). Might just be my preferences though. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>SEGA Mega Drive Mini (Electronic Games)</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>https://www.amazon.co.uk</distributor>
          <publisher>amazon</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Alexey Stepanov</name>
          <title>Sega Does What Nintendon't - again! </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Essential for everyone who gets shivers from the above ad, or games like Sonic the
            Hedgehog, Toejam and Earl, Comix zone, Gun Star heroes, Streets of Rage and Earthworm
            Jim, among others. Sega had just one job - to treat both fans and games with respect,
            and they have not failed, unlike Sony. Everything works as it should, and it does feel a
            'complete' package, even though most will find one or more of their favourite games
            missing from the included list - but you cannot have it all, I suppose. From the sounds
            to different 'box art' when you switch languages, you can see how much attention and
            LOVE was put into it. Highly, highly recommended. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Kevin Muldoon</name>
          <title>If You Loved the SEGA Mega Drive, You'll Love The SEGA Mega Drive Mini! </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Ever since Nintendo released the NES Mini, mini versions of classic gaming consoles
            have been all the rage. Now it's SEGA's Turn. Various versions of the Sega Mega Drive
            has been released by third-parties over the years, but this is the first official
            re-release of the Mega Drive from SEGA themselves. The package includes: * SEGA Mega
            Drive Mini * Two Wired Controllers * HDMI Cable * USB Power Cable (No USB wall adapter
            is included) The console itself is fantastic. SEGA has done an amazing job here. Even
            the cartridge slot opens up (of course, it isn't used for anything). The controllers
            look exactly like the original. Apart from the USB port being at the end of the
            controller cable, you'd struggle to tell the difference. The D-pad works great and the
            buttons are responsive. Games play great too. There aren't too many settings to play
            around with, but you can play games in the original 4:3 aspect ratio or go full screen.
            All 42 games are presented well. You can view them all using the front cover or side
            sleeve. All games can be sorted in a variety of ways, such as genre, release date,
            number of players etc. There's a good variety of games such as Sonic 1 and 2, Strider,
            Street Fighter II, Ecco the Dolphin, Road Rage 2, Tetris, and more. It's a little
            annoying though that no sports games have been included as the Mega Drive had many
            classics. Online play would have been great too, but overall I am really pleased. SEGA
            have did a fantastic job recreating the design of the original console and the included
            controllers are superb. If you aren't a massic retro gamer, you may want to just buy the
            Sega Mega Drive Classics game instead, but I think most people who grew up with the Mega
            Drive will love this :) Kevin </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">matthew phillip</name>
          <title>Looks good now I have the Mega CD tower kit </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>So happy I had this now, got the original as seen in pic, games are amazing and looks
            good with the Mega CD tower add on I imported from Japan. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">DaveC2020</name>
          <title>Loving this Retro Console </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I received my Mega Drive Mini console today 6 months after preorder and is just
            brilliant. Attention to detail is remarkable like the cartridge slot, volume control,
            reset button and power button on the console. Played all the games and brought back
            memories. Console is reasonably priced and arrived in excellent condition. One downside
            is games like Street Fighter 2 Champion Edition that are better played using a 6 button
            controller. The two controllers that come with the console each have 3 buttons. Bought a
            Retro Bit 6 button controller on Amazon for around £20 and highly recommend it. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mark.O</name>
          <title>Brilliant ,best of the mini consoles so far,sorry SNES </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Brilliant to play the mega drive again in its original form.i always preferred this
            design over the mega drive 2 and its ugly mega cd add on.really well made console true
            to the original albeit a mini version and using the controllers again feels great after
            all this time.build quality and box is great and accurate for the original and really
            kicks it home that sega is trying to give it the true mega drive feel unlike the dodgy
            blaze mega drives that have been around for some time.there some great games on here,I
            think there’s 42 altogether and most of them were really good back in the day of my
            youth and my all time favourite road rash 2 makes an appearance.personally I think the
            game choice is the best out of all the mini consoles so far. the emulation so far seems
            accurate and the sound too.you can also choose full screen or bordered in the menu and
            also switch to crt for that true retro feel.connects via hdmi to all modern TVs and is
            powered by your TVs USB port so you don’t need a plug if you have usb on your tv.all in
            all you are getting an accurate mini mega drive with some of the best games on the
            console faithfully reproduced for the equivalent of about £2 a game so why are you
            reading this and not ordering it?its great for people who owned the original and also
            new retro gamers wanting to experience the mega drive without having to pay crazy money
            buying originals in good condition.well worth it,awesome mini console </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Nigel Powell</name>
          <title>Not quite four stars but three would be harsh (3.75) </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The good: Exquisite design on the console, best of any mini console yet in my opinion,
            the details are great, a real collectors gem. The two controllers supplied are excellent
            quality and perfect reproductions of the original with a decent cable length unlike
            Nintendo's efforts. Standard USB connectors as well should offer good compatibility with
            other formats (as yet untested). A good number of games and a very easy to use and well
            designed UI with box art and easy to understand settings and more importantly, easily
            accessed from the controller during gameplay, again unlike Nintendo's efforts. Games are
            perfectly responsive and look good on a modern TV although large screens may be less
            forgiving due to the low resolution used back then. Overall the best emulation yet
            outside of PC and less 'official' emulation but not perfect (see The Ugly below). The
            bad: Selection of games could be better. I know this is personal preference but there
            are some glaring omissions. Where are the Sega arcade classics like OutRun and
            Afterburner. Why only Streets of Rage 2 (admittedly the best one!), Shinobi 3 but no
            Revenge of Shinobi? I'm sure licensing has played a part here but the collection does
            feel a little incomplete. Whilst excellent quality the controllers provided are only the
            three button variety which makes playing Street Fighter 2 a pain but this one game
            shouldn't be a deal breaker and there is an excellent 6 button pad available which works
            perfectly with this device. Also, without the inevitable hacking, there is no scope for
            firmware updates or adding games, something that the second generation Flashback HD has
            a distinct advantage over this device. The Ugly: The CRT filter is a shocker, worst
            attempt I've ever seen and should be avoided at all costs. Unfortunately this leaves no
            options for smoothing the pixels on a modern TV. You can stretch the image to fit
            widescreen but I personally think this is even worse unless you prefer fat sprites of
            course. My biggest issue however is that there is sound lag with the audio a few frames
            behind the visuals, not quite as bad as the AT Games consoles but it is still
            noticeable, especially on the quicker games like the Sonic games where it seems worst.
            Also, I do own the original console and the sound isn't quite perfect on some games but
            honestly for most people this won't be an issue; but the lag is annoying as AT Games
            were criticised quite heavily on this point so it's probably only fair to point it out
            on this device as well. It's better but not perfect. Overall: Best HD Megadrive console
            yet but not perfect and not a clear winner for me over the second gen Flashback HD as
            there are pluses and minus' for and against each when going head to head. If you have to
            get one and don't have a collection of cartridges to test and you're not bothered about
            the the odd missing title here and there it's a no brainer. Either way you're gonna have
            sound lag!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Adam F</name>
          <title>Just get one </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I own most of the mini consoles from the NES to the C64, I also still have original
            Nintendo's and most importantly to this review, my megadrive! I also own many of the
            games on the console, and all are great reproductions. From Castle of illusion to Sonic
            to Alex Kidd, they are all great games, and I cannot wait for my son to be old enough to
            play them, I'd recommend this for a youngster as a first "console". The console itself
            is up there and maybe better cosmetically than the Nintendo's, and is possibly the best
            mini console yet, but that may be just because this is my era and I was a Sega kid.
            Coming with 2 controllers is great, and they are of a good quality, although one does
            sometimes double click on the pad when it shouldn't, that may go away with use over
            time. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Romek</name>
          <title>Probably the best official Retro Console so far </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>So this is a very solid retro console. Build quality is very good, attention to detail
            is great. Love how most of the buttons on the console actually work. Well done Sega...
            now here is what would have made this absolutely amazing: Include the 6-button
            controller (especially since some of the games use it -hello Street Fighter, and the
            Japanese version got the 6-button controllers). Put a working audio jack in the front
            (like the original). I think that would have been very helpful and pretty easy to do
            (hello Raspberry Pi) Standard 6-button USB Sega controllers don't all work??!!? Not sure
            what's going on there but I have 2 different ones and both are not recognised by the
            console. (work great on my Raspberry Pi so I know they use generic drivers). The game
            library is nearly a masterpiece with a few games I would have swapped out to make
            perfect (I know this is more of an opinion but you might agree with some of these):
            remove: World of Illusion Probotector Story of Thor Virtual Fighter 2 Eternal Champions
            Dynamite Headdy Light Crusader Replace with some of these: Phantasy Star II Phantasy
            Star III Super Street Fighter 2 Sonic and Knuckles Revenge of Shinobi Thunder Force 2
            Gain Ground Air Buster Crack Down Batman Shadow Dancer E-Swat Granada Castlevania
            Bloodlines Vector Man 2 Disney's Aladdin Herzog Zwei Gaiares Shinning Force Shinning
            Force 2 Shinning in the Darkness and I can go on... Better yet, charge twice the price
            and add ALL of these! :-) </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Martin Ward</name>
          <title>High Definition Graphics, Stereo Sound </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This is an entertaining trip down nostalgia lane, back to the days when high definition
            meant something else entirely. A selection of some of the greatest games of the 16 bit
            era, from an age as golden as the logo on the console casing. Despite emulation being
            nearly as old as the mega drive itself, there is no substitute for playing on genuine
            hardware. With this being Sega’s first console since the days of the Dreamcast, it was
            unthinkable for a fanatic like myself to pass it up. I’ve waited ages for something this
            good. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>The Mendocino Hotel and Garden Suites</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>https://www.expedia.com</distributor>
          <publisher>expedia</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.S.A.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Claudia</name>
          <title>Pleasing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Good value. Shared bathroom not really nice. Otherwise there is a lot of value for
            money. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">John</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Cool old inn. Charm maintained throughout. Friendly staff </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Brent</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Beautiful turn of the century hotel with multiple accommodation options depending on
            your budget. On the main boardwalk in Mendocino, and steps away from the coastal walking
            trails. Staff were friendly, and accommodating. (John Tw.. was very funny and
            entertaining). Meals were good and reasonably priced. We would have stayed longer if we
            could have.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">by A verified traveler</name>
          <title>Pleasing </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Location and employees are great. Very nice restoration of the facility.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Patti</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great dining. Location is tops. Views. I have stayed here many times. A great place to
            have family stays.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">OPenaloza</name>
          <title>Pleasing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Needs some updating inside and outside (fix broken fencing, cleanup weeds in gardens
            etc. otherwise nice place and can be updated again. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">BillH</name>
          <title>Pleasing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The room was very small and access to the double bed was limited to one side. The bed
            was very high which made getting on the bed a problem. The hotel advertised WiFi but the
            signal was too weak to be usable in our room. The shared baths were OK for a short
            stray. An OK night's sleep at a decent price in an expensive town.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Haird</name>
          <title>OK</title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Location is very good, but so is anyplace in town. Facility was cramped and rooms were
            worn. Not terrible, but not a good value at the price. They really ought to upgrade
            their mattresses which are saggy like a hammock. Shower temp was hard to keep
            stable.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">mary</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>We have stayed here many times. Staff is extremely friendly. Rooms are old fashioned
            and great views. Just a nice place to stay. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">by A verified traveler</name>
          <title>OK</title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Old quirky hotel. Nice staff but very squeaky bed. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">by A verified traveler</name>
          <title>Good, Not great</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great Location with lots of lovely local history. I think they would do well to WASH
            the windows in the room I had 315, and perhaps the curtains as well. I get that the
            hotel is over 150 years old, but I dont want it to feel like I am in a 150year old room.
            It was clean otherwise, not a lot of modern day amenities such as outlets. It did have a
            semi-damp/musty smell and although you could put the windows up, not only were they not
            clean, they didnt have screens, definite minus </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Anne</name>
          <title>Disappointing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The history of the hotel was impressive but otherwise we regretted having booked here.
          </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
</teiCorpus>
