<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE teiCorpus SYSTEM "./tei_corpus.dtd">
<teiCorpus>
  <teiHeader>
    <!--File description-->
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <!--Title, author and encoding's responsable-->
        <title>Corpus of reviews</title>
        <author xml:id="auth">
          <persName xml:lang="it">
            <forename>Alessandro </forename>
            <surname>Mazzeo</surname>
          </persName>
        </author>
        <respStmt xml:id="AM">
          <resp>Reviews taken by:</resp>
          <persName>
            <forename>Alessandro</forename>
            <surname>Mazzeo</surname>
          </persName>
        </respStmt>
      </titleStmt>
      <!--Information about editions-->
      <editionStmt>
        <p>1' edition <date>2019</date></p>
      </editionStmt>
      <!--Information about distribution-->
      <publicationStmt>
        <distributor>Alessandro Mazzeo</distributor>
        <publisher>Alessandro Mazzeo</publisher>
        <availability status="restricted">
          <licence>Creative Commons 4.0 BY SA</licence>
        </availability>
      </publicationStmt>
      <!--Information about the source where the content is taken-->
      <sourceDesc>
        <p>Born digital</p>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <!--Information about encoding-->
    <encodingDesc>
      <!--Project's purpose-->
      <projectDesc>
        <p> The project is a electronic corpus of reviews about products or services, taken from
          e-commerce and others booking platform. </p>
      </projectDesc>
      <!--Declaration about common encoding editing-->
      <editorialDecl>
        <p>Every text element is original.</p>
      </editorialDecl>
    </encodingDesc>
    <!--Not bibliographic description: text language and text typology-->
    <profileDesc>
      <textClass>
        <keywords>
          <term>corpus</term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="EN">English</language>
      </langUsage>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <TEI>
    <!-- Reviews of a product -->
    <teiHeader>
      <!-- Product or service information -->
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>Kitchen Herb Garden Kit Windowsill Window Box Planter with Seeds</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>Primrose</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.amazon.co.uk/</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <!-- One review of the product or service inserted in teiHeader for this element TEI-->
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">MB</name>
          <title>Kind of works</title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Like most people I didn't have much luck growing the seeds provided so bought some more
            which have grown I also planted spring onions as these are easy to grow. The growing
            material provided is quite sandy so I found I had to add a fair bit of water to get
            anything to appear. Id suggest different amounts for the 3 pots provided and hopefully
            one will yield resilts. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <!-- Another review of the product or service inserted in teiHeader-->
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">monica smith</name>
          <title>Absolutely rubbish.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Very disappointing. I followed the instructions and I am a frequent gardener, yet
            nothing has happened. They haven’t germinated or sprouted - after being planted for 6
            weeks already not a single peep of life is happening in any of the boxes. I’m going to
            put it down to a bad batch of seeds. The soil is also a bit odd, but I’m not sure. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">J. M. Cadle</name>
          <title>Good present</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Bought as gifts and seem to be well received. The box was smaller than I thought but
            the measurements were on it - not a problem as will easily fit on a windowsill. Well
            packed and received on time. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Zac</name>
          <title>Didnt grow anything</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>no chillies gre after following all instructions, very disappointing. Went out and
            bought some soil to replace the non suitable growing medium they give you and some new
            chilli seeds and already i can see green shoots poking through. basicly you are just
            buying the box ignore the other stuff it gives you probably could of just bought a small
            plastic flower trough for the window sill and got the same effect for cheaper.
            disappointing fathers day present. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Amazon Customer</name>
          <title>One Star</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Seeds did not germinate at all</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Hg</name>
          <title>Use ur own seeds.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I'm like most reviewers, unfortunately nothing grew. It's definitely the seeds. I used
            the same soil with different seeds and they are coming on a treat. Would've been 5 stars
            but not this time sorry☹. If u can live with that and use our own seeds then this is the
            one for u. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Earthling</name>
          <title>DONT BUY</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Total waste of money, don’t know what the potting compost was supposed to be, looked
            like granulated cork, 30 seeds planted on a warm south facing windowsill on a
            propergating mat, over a month later, nothing, total loss of money, also did not have
            any instructions or planting directions at all, very cheap and nasty, also much smaller
            than I expected </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">NR82</name>
          <title>What a waste of time and money</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>What a waste of time and money. Quite literally nothing grew after weeks of waiting.
            Planted several other herbs at the same time from normal seed packets in normal soil and
            all are doing fine. This kit comes with a very strange gritty sand to grow the seeds in
            and I strongly believe this is what has prevented any growth. Don’t bother with this
            item </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>Derwent Academy 2300147 Colouring Pencils and Graphite Pencils Art Supplies Set of
            30 Pencils and 5 Accessories</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>Derwent</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.amazon.co.uk/</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Debbie Parker</name>
          <title>Value for money.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Derwent pencils are a well known brand and are made in the UK. I got them as started
            kit for myself, rediscovering an old hobby. This set is ideal for my needs as it has a
            mixture of vibrant colour pencils , water colours and graphite pencils. All of great
            quality. As a first set i feel this would be a really good gift for a budding artist or
            someone getting back into art. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">P. Callaway</name>
          <title>Very happy daughter</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Perfectly adequate set for a keen little artist. It is by no means the best quality
            box, but it works and it stores everything together and there is a good range of
            materials inside for the drawing and sketching she wants to do. I am no artist so can't
            comment on the quality of the actual pencils, but they do the trick and she doesn't seem
            to have to press unduly hard to get them to work. The watercolour pencil marks retain
            good colour when 'diluted' and I think this is a really good value buy. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">vicky</name>
          <title>Very nice present for a young artist</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I have recently purchased Derwent pencils for my 14 year old daughter who loves drawing
            and was unsure what different types of pencils to buy for her. I bought this set as a
            Christmas present and it comes nicely presented in a wooden box with some different
            pencils so she can try and decide which she likes best </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">jenny waller</name>
          <title>Nice set</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I brought this set as a present, I can only say what I think by looking at it, very
            nice set, perfect for young artist, everything is in the set, well presented, light and
            easy to carry, I think this present will go down well</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">LucyRice</name>
          <title>Recommend</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I really love this and it’s great weather your a beginner artist or just want to draw.
            I love how it comes with water color pencils as well as regular one though I would
            suggest having more colors to choose from on both sides </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Careen Marie</name>
          <title>Great</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Comes in a lovely box, My 15 year old was made up, as she loves water colour paint, but
            never has tried pencils.... She said they are really good to work with, and a good make
            too.... So, pleased all round... Would make a lovely gift, as I bought it for...... </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">michael t.</name>
          <title>A touch dissatisfied</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Good set to get started and the case is very handy, although I felt the price was high
            and I was a little disappointed in quality and size, I found it more for coloring or
            watercolour as apposed to a drawing set with more of a selection of drawing and
            sketching pencils charcoals ect. It was also smaller than expected. However that being
            said I did enjoy using it but maybe add more drawing essentials. I didn't feel as
            professional as I thought it would for price. But enjoyed a few scribbles anyhow. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Bazil</name>
          <title>Nice set for the bidding artist</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Got these for my daughter (7) to stop her leaving pencils all over the place. So far so
            good on that one. She loves them as they're a really nicely presented set and the
            colours are strong and bright. Pencils are great quality and sharpen nicely. All can be
            bought in smaller sets so can be replaced like for like as they're used so they should
            stay nice for some time. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>GTA San Andreas (Xbox 360)</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>ROCKSTAR</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.amazon.co.uk/</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Dogshark</name>
          <title>Possibly the best game ever.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Bought for the brother-in-law and his kids. What can I say thats not already been said
            about this game. Epic, classic, awesome. Lost count how many times I've played this,
            sold it, changed console, bought it again, played it again.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Sebastian Fernandez</name>
          <title>Classic!</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Super happy that Xbox remade a legendary game. 100% recommended!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Andrew O'Neill</name>
          <title>An old classic.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>A perfect open world. An abundance of things to do. This game will suck you into
            another world. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Dave W</name>
          <title>Excellent service</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great son loved it fast dispatch</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">tracy</name>
          <title>Item as decribed</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Ordered for my brother as he is a fan of these games - he loves it. Arrived on time,
            within estimated delivery date and item as described. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">P. Marck</name>
          <title>It's the same version as is on the Xbox Store.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This Xbox 360 re-release is based on the HD remaster that has replaced the Original
            Xbox edition on the Xbox Store, so that's to say, you're getting the same experience as
            gamers who purchased the digital version at launch for £2.99. Is it good or great? It's
            somewhere between the two considering this is was ported from the iOS to the 360, so
            things like the menus and elsewhere will feel laggy and out of place but most of the
            time it's fine. No issues. Anyhow, if you'd like to purchase the physical release
            GameSeek has it for £12.99 (a pound cheaper on the Xbox Store for the digital release).
          </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">teeside tin tin 190185</name>
          <title>would be better if were not for the bugs!</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>It was great when it first came out 11 years ago and being re-released for the 360 was
            worth the wait. Its as how I first remember it but its let down by bugs firstly the life
            is a beach mission which despite hitting the buttons in tune to the music u still won't
            get 2500 points so the only way is to hit them out of sync to progress. And secondly the
            music tracks from the fictional radio stations skip halfway through a song to the next
            one which is mildy irritating to say the least. Other than that its still a good game
            with the graphics looking a bit smoother coupled with a retro hip hop outlook making it
            still an essential purchase. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">bobknot</name>
          <title>More bugs than an entomologist's workshop</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I really can't believe that this has scored 4 stars (I'm only giving it one because I
            have to)... Don't get me wrong, it's a brilliant game and it's great fun to play (it's
            GTA after all) - but that's only if and when you can play it, if you can play it at all.
            This version of the game is absolutely full of bugs! Most you can learn to live with
            like the lag or audio cutting out now and again, jerky cars etc. Some are tediously
            frustrating but not the end of the world like a crash or glitch that means lost data
            following the need to reboot. But for me, the game has just gotten to that point where
            it is no longer playable. After 24 hours and 40% progress the game refuses to load the
            next and only mission I can do to progress the story so I've essentially wasted £15 (and
            a day of my life). Seriously, read the forums (I wish I had) - they're full of reports
            of seemingly endless bugs and crashes and games becoming unplayable, save files becoming
            corrupted and more. This version of the game was released nearly a year ago and it seems
            there are no updates or patches available to address any of these issues. It seems to me
            like Rockstar have ported an already buggy game from the mobile platform onto the 360
            just to make a quick buck and by doing so have done a massive massive disservice to long
            term fans of the franchise. I missed this on the original Xbox way back in 2005 so was
            incredibly excited to find out this existed - but my experience has left me rather
            bitter and I'm not sure that I would play another GTA again. My recommendation would be
            to save yourself £15 and a lot of wasted hours, or spend that money on an original Xbox
            and get a copy for that. Disappointment is a HUGE understatement. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>Sony PlayStation Classic Console</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>SONY</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.amazon.co.uk/</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Bobby Dazzler</name>
          <title>Very dissappointed</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I was one of the first people in the UK to get hold of the very original PS1, so that
            makes me old I know. However my memory isn't that bad, I loaded and tried to play Tekken
            3 and Ridge Racer 4 and a few others. They did load, albeit having to wait for them to
            load. But the frame rate, blurry pixels (no not quite my eyesight yet) no up-scaling,
            borders on the edge no fancy rendering made my heart sink. This is terrible. GTA has
            truly awful emulation. I know things have moved on, but the emulation was horrible. I
            was not expecting HD remasters of every single game, but a lot of them had issues with
            sound and frame rates and general unresponsiveness. Never have I been so disappointed.
            Maybe I should have waited for these reviews, I definitely would not have bought it. I
            do NOT recommend this item however tempting it sounds. Honestly you are better off
            sourcing the originals and getting a PS3 or a PS2 that can play PS1 games.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Nathan Payne</name>
          <title>Could have and should have been better</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The hardware itself looks amazing. It is everything you would expect a mini PlayStation
            to look like. The controllers are also great to use. The library of games is a mixed bag
            but PlayStation has so many great games that it would be impossible to pick games
            everyone loved so overall I am happy with the selected games. That is where the good
            review stops... Shoddy implementation of emulation, poor choice of PAL version games and
            worse performance than original hardware mean this product is useless as a game console.
            I still have original hardware and a few of the games the classic has pre-loaded. When
            gameplay is compared it is like night and day, the classic is a horrible experience with
            slowdowns, worse graphics and graphical bugs. Not to mention the stutter and low
            framerates. There also audio issues on some games which are very obvious. This was 100%
            avoidable as the hardware within the classic should be more than capable of producing an
            experience better than original hardware, never mind just matching it! </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">J R heartly</name>
          <title>One star for no discs?? We knew that!</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I can’t understand people complaining about 20 games, their favourite not being on
            here, no dualshock or not being able to change discs. (It’s almost smaller than a disc).
            If they refer to the disc changer button, that does work on games (that had multiple
            discs) when you are up to the part in tha game where a disc change is needed.... FF7
            etc. I read about this on the Sony website before I bought it. Also it seems people may
            have forgotten that this is an old console and their phones are more powerful. So the
            games are a little scruffy in parts and frames dropped on the original. The graphics
            aren’t amazing. They weren’t in 1995. I don’t like 100% of the games. So I don’t play
            them. I do love some of the games and these run well, look good, play well and I’m happy
            I bought it. Like the nes and snes. Some games aren’t ones you will like. You can’t add
            or take any away (unless it’s hacked). Like those “consoles”, it’s an emulator. It’s not
            an actual console. It’s a piece of nostalgia. (Memberberries) And for that it does a
            good job. Any company making one would be accused of Ripping off Nintendo. Research
            before you buy. I bought it when it was just a few games revealed and knew their were no
            dualshocks. It’s not perfect. But it’s fun to play the old games with old style
            controllers. (Update) I’ve had a few comments on this review so I thought I’d respond.
            Their comments are all correct and I thank them for posting. Analysis has shown this
            does not perform as well as the original. In some cases 3 FPS are dropped, in other case
            10 FPS (from 60-50). In some cases the sounds is off and the visuals blurred. Though I
            must say without sarcasm. When I play it. I don’t play it with FAPS counting the frames
            per second. I don’t play it side by side with the original to make comparison. I do play
            it for the games and I still enjoy it. (Personal opinion). Statistics are good and
            correct. But I didn’t buy it for stats. The SNES mini also drops frames , sounds are off
            and has some colour changes to the original. Also facts by analysis by better people
            than I. But I must admit not as noticeable as the PS classic. My point being it’s not
            perfect, especially if compared statistically and side by side. It could have been
            better and would have been nice if it was a perfect recreation. I just play mine. And I
            enjoy it. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">J. Dix</name>
          <title>Cheap cash grab</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The selection of games is subjective of course, but this system has a few glaring
            omissions in my view, which lowered my original expectations considerably - Tomb Raider
            and Crash Bandicoot to name just two. That’s not the biggest problem however. The system
            looks pretty good and the build quality seems excellent but the emulation is just
            terrible. Games from this era haven’t aged particularly well in general, but the in
            house emulators used for the PS3 and vita run these games much better than this. The
            games look awful and are slow and laggy - tekken 3 and twisted metal are borderline
            unplayable. The interface is bare bones and there are no options to add filters or
            borders around the games (this doesn’t bother me particularly but it may be worth
            bearing in mind). There are certainly a handful of “classic” games on here, but if I
            decide to play Tekken, Resident Evil or Final Fantasy 7, it will be on my old PS3 where
            the performance is far superior. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>NESCAFE Dolce Gusto Oblo Coffee Machine by Krups - Black </title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>Nescafe</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.amazon.co.uk/</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Darren Dean</name>
          <title>Compact</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>This early Christmas present from my partner and I love it. Very easy to use and clean.
            Ok there have been comments that the water tank is not that big and it isn't but it is
            very easy to remove and fill and also makes the unit compact for small kitchens. Love
            expresso and my partner Latte' and the coffees are delicious and will be trying more
            from the wide range. This is a manual machine which I like as the amounts are not pre-
            measured you just switch on and stop when you are ready which makes it easy to adjust
            your coffee to how you like it. Extremely well priced too </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Connell F.</name>
          <title>apart from the SHOCKING bright RED electric cord ... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Yes, that's right. It comes with a bright red electric cord, the kind that looks like
            you bought an extension cord at a DIY store, and no, it probably won't go with anything
            else in your kitchen. But if you can get past that, the cartoon instructions don't
            provide enough info to make proper coffee. Put the pod in, way too much water, no
            auto-shut off after sending the water through so the water keeps going and going. No
            additional instructions or troubleshooting ideas about what to do. But the cartoon is
            available in 20 or so languages. Also small water capacity. I expected a lot more from a
            company like Krups. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">cfb</name>
          <title>Very easy to use</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>On unboxing this item I thought it was a little smaller than expected. It holds around
            2x 300ml cups worth of water just over if filled full. This machine however is great. We
            already had the pods and glasses so just needed the machine. On the top you have a power
            button which when pressed first time takes around 20/30 secs till it turns green
            indicating its ready to use. There also a lever which goes left to right for hot or cold
            water, when switched to hot it starts to pour your drink and one switch back to the
            centre possition stops the pour, so no overspill mess to clean up. Its very easy to use
            and makes great coffee with the pods. At this price Id highly reccomend it, especially
            if your new to the coffee machine ownership game. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">MrTwo</name>
          <title>A good machine which makes a great coffee.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>My wife loves her Nescafe Dolce Gusto machine, this is her 4th over a 8 year period (or
            so), the machine provides a good quality cup of coffee in one of many flavours/styles.
            The capsules are available from supermarkets though some stock more flavours than
            others, they aren't cheap but when compared to a coffee shop you get up to 16 capsules
            for only a little more than a single shop coffee (at one of the chains). On purchasing
            the machine we also received a voucher for £10 off the Dolce Gusto online store plus
            each box of capsules has a code which allows you to, at present, enter a competition to
            win a year supply of coffee (not sure how long this is valid for and whether it will be
            updated to a new competition once it ends). The machine is well designed and looks good
            in any time of kitchen, this machine is wider than it is deep which allows it to perch
            on the edge somewhere, the water is added to a reservoir on the back of the machine and
            the capsule is placed in the front. Now right at the start I said that this was our 4th
            machine and that is partially due to one issue, this only happened on our last machine
            (the earlier ones wore out after a decent length of life), ensure there is water in the
            reservoir, we made the mistake of turning on the machine with very little water and then
            walking away and it never recovered. A good machine which makes a great coffee. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Eddie M.</name>
          <title>Great machine, but very noisy compared to other models ... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great machine, but very noisy compared to other models (Melody) we have at work. That
            said the coffee is great and hotter than the melody machines we have at work. It has a
            1ltr capacitywhich gives 4 - 8 cups, depends on type of pod used. Value for money is off
            the scale at under £40, I've seen this model advertised and on sale from £89 (ASDA) to
            £119 (ARGOS). </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mr. D. Green</name>
          <title>An okay product if you don't mind a warm, but not hot drink! </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>it's a reasonabel product for the price, but there are two major problems which effect
            the quality of the drink. 1. The machine doesn't dispense a set amount of liquid, which
            makes it difficult when you need to measure two different amounts for most drinks 2.
            when dispense, the drink needs to consumed very quickly because it isn't very hot- we
            have tried different ways of increasing the heat (but we shouldn't have to), these
            include warming the cup and filling the machine up with hot water. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Rob</name>
          <title>Don't Buy - LEAKING.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The product was leaking water out the back after using the coffee pod to pour a cup of
            coffee. If I wasn't lazy, I would have complained and sent the item back for a full
            refund. That was the second machine (exact same product) I've had problems with. So I
            went and purchased a Moccamaster coffee machine. It's more expensive but so so so much
            better than these cheap Krups machines. Get yourself a real coffee machine folks,
            they're just as easy and convenient to use but deliver a much better taste of
            coffee.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Murph</name>
          <title>Does The Job </title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Bought this for my girlfriend for Christmas as she loves her coffee! I must admit the
            novelty seems to have worn off, as I can't remember the last time she has had a coffee
            using this machine. Even so, anytime that I use it I do enjoy the coffee that is made
            from it. I do enjoy having a fancy coffee every now and again using this, other than the
            normal old fashioned way of having a coffee. Not bad at all.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>NASA Shuttle Launch Into Rainbow Premium Graphic T-Shirt </title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>Amazon</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.amazon.co.uk/</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Lizzie</name>
          <title>Sizing too small</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Nice t-shirt but far too small, would recommend buying at least one size bigger </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Bee</name>
          <title>Beautifully made.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I loved this. Bought for my husband as a gift, it was worth the wait to arrive (one
            week) as it was clearly hand printed and was brilliantly done. The colours remain vivid
            after several washes and he loves it so made me happy. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">cerys</name>
          <title>BEST PURCHASE EVER!!!</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>In complete awe of this tshirt! Super 80s vibes, got it in the biggest size and it's
            super baggy and comfy! (I'm size woman's 18/20) Awesome for tucking into trousers or
            just lazing about. Love how environmentally friendly this brand is, came without any
            plastic and a small slip saying the way they print is even planet friendly which is just
            awesome. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Rob A</name>
          <title>I opened the parcel and wasn't disappointed, having cast an eye on the size of ... </title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Bought as a gift for my Brother, I opened the parcel and wasn't disappointed, having
            cast an eye on the size of the t-shirt, it seems to be spot on. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Roo Black</name>
          <title>Great product</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I bought this for my husband. The colours are great and the design is really eye
            catching and the cotton is soft and feels good quality. Gave it a quick wash before he
            wore it to remove the vinegar smell, as advised by the company. Really happy with this
            purchase. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Nick_Swansea</name>
          <title>Nice print, quality t-shirt</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>True to size and a very nice print. Wish I'd bought another different NASA t-shirt
            during the Amazon Prime Day.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Linda</name>
          <title>Great T-shirt</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>My daughter bought this for her brother’s birthday. He really likes it. It washes well
            and is comfortable to wear.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Jasmine Williams Davies</name>
          <title>Tiny sizes</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The size chart is horrendous, an Xl in Women's is more like a small. Very dissapointed.
            Want my money back!! </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>The Lodge at Strichen</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>https://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.tripadvisor.co.uk</publisher>
          <pubPlace>U.K.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Irene M</name>
          <title>Amazing toasties!</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Lunchtime visit following a walk round the community park. Spotlessly clean and
            tastefully decorated with lovely artwork displayed for sale. Had coffee and a cheese and
            haggis (yes, haggis!) toastie with side salad, slaw and couscous - gorgeous!! Friendly,
            attentive staff. Can’t wait to return to sample the traybakes on another day! A real
            jewel!!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Maagenta</name>
          <title>Excellent Lunch with Fantastic Service </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Had lunch at the Lodge yesterday with a friend. My friend has special dietary needs due
            to allergies, nothing was too much trouble. I asked for a couple of extras, again no
            trouble at all. Waitress was lovely and could not do enough for us. The food was
            excellent. Definitely be back - thank you for a great meal , great service and lovely
            surroundings </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Lizzie</name>
          <title>Food is fine but staff need improvement</title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Food I would describe as above average pub fare. What really let this place down were
            the staff. No-one greeted us as we came in or even smiled the whole time we were there.
            Every member of staff had a sour expression on their faces. Their attitudes made the
            whole experience very uncomfortable. Wont be going back again anytime soon.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">_gillianjen</name>
          <title>Afternoon tea</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Had a fantastic afternoon tea here, it was brilliant value for money and would have
            been happy with getting half of what we got ! We were given boxes to take home all the
            delicious fancy cakes we couldn’t eat and they were just as good when we had them later
            on . I would definitely recommend for an afternoon tea and the service was excellent ,
            the staff are really attentive and welcoming .</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">funkylady</name>
          <title>Epic breakfast rolls</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Stopped here late morning to refuel for our cycle. Surprised to read some reports re
            poor service as we had no problems and sat outside. We have had plenty breakfast rolls
            on our cycle travels in the NE Scotland and can honestly say the sausage bap was epic!
            The bacon and egg one my other half had was equally as good. Arrived promptly with hot
            tea. We will be back!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">lovemeena</name>
          <title>Ediocre bacon roll</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Sat outside the Lodge to enjoy a bacon roll and coffee(not allowed to sit in with my
            daft dog. Shame as Strichen Community Park is so very dog friendly). My order was
            processed albeit with some confusion because I was sitting outside (blame the
            dog..wouldn't have happened if I had sat inside). Ordered processed and delivered in a
            very short while. The waitress was attentive and professional...Thank you. Pity the
            bacon roll was full of dry back bacon( tip, a little steam on the flat top goes along
            way to making moist,flavorsome bacon). Coffee was mediocre(they serve the same brand in
            is an establishment not 30 miles away and it is far better. Maybe your Baristas need to
            exchange tips? Price: Way to expensive, £6.10 for coffee and a bacon buttie is close to
            daylight robbery! Won't becoming back. Well not to the Lodge anyways. The park is a
            perfect place to walk my dog, just a shame the "pitstop" won't be the Lodge!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">ireneh987</name>
          <title>Coffees</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Went here for a coffee in the afternoon good coffee and a selection of Homebakes Clean
            well presented and a lovely outlook. Staff were pleasant</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Elizabeth_perryxx</name>
          <title>Concerned for a waitressl</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Went for our lunch this weekend and the food was great, couldn’t fault them at all for
            that. But was slightly concerned for a waitress with glasses and blonde hair. She seemed
            quite flustered when serving us and initially I thought it was because they were very
            busy (which is great!) but when watching her for a few moments I did realise that
            another blonde waitress was being quite rude to her. I don’t blame the owners what so
            ever but in my opinion this is very unprofessional and the poor girl with the glasses
            should be able to do her job in peace.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">ImReallyAnElf</name>
          <title>Good menu and comfortable</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The cafe is comfortable and the menu is good - I especially recommend the specialist
            fishcakes - with pleasant servers. However, it's got very busy since the new owners took
            it over, so it's advisable to book a table in advance if you want to be sure of eating
            lunch here. It's child friendly. Breakfasts are good if you're there early enough, with
            staff willing to substitute for example the haggis for an extra egg.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">hattoncple</name>
          <title>Disappointing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>After reading the reviews we went for a breakfast after a walk around the park.
            Although the service was good the food itself was average to say the least. Warm over
            cooked bacon overcooked egg undercooked tattie scone and small portion to put it mildly.
            Nice premises but wont be rushing back anytime soon!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">mrrae</name>
          <title>Poor service.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="1">1/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Decided whilst out walking the dog that we would stop at one of the lodges outside
            tables for coffee and cake. We ordered inside and were brought 2 paper cups of
            completely milk drowned coffee..no sugar or stirrers offered and our cakes in a bag.
            Surely our order could have been brought in proper cups and plates??? We would have
            brought them back inside once finished?? Unimpressed......</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Shaun S</name>
          <title>amazing food</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>amazing food and amazing staff easy to park and a lovey place warm food and great to
            eat in or takeaway</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Lucy S</name>
          <title>Outstanding food and friendly service</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>I took my 2 very young children for a walk and a spot of lunch, we felt very welcome
            and at ease in the lodge. Staff were friendly and approachable, nothing seemed like too
            much effort. The place was lovely and clean, considering park goers also seem to use the
            toilets. Food was lovely and to a high standard, the children’s meals were brilliant,
            not only did they have colourful plates but were offered their own colourful cutlery too
            (which I have not experienced in the past) this was most definitely a thoughtful touch!
            I will 100% be returning to the lodge for more delicious food!</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
  <TEI>
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
          <title>Ercolino e Savi Montecatini T.</title>
          <author ref="#auth"/>
        </titleStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
          <distributor>https://www.expedia.com/</distributor>
          <publisher>https://www.expedia.com/</publisher>
          <pubPlace>I.T.</pubPlace>
        </publicationStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
          <p>Born digital: no previous source exists.</p>
        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Marcy</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Beautiful hotel in great location. Fantastic breakfast. AMAZING dinner.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Gianni</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Staff was wonderful !! Location is perfect, there are many restaurants near the hotel. The rooms were spacious, clean and the air conditioning was cold. Everything about our stay was fantastic. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">by A verified traveler</name>
          <title>Pleasing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Very clean and pleasant hotel, looks very smart from the roadside. Bright and clean room though could have been a little bigger Nice patio around the outside to sit and have a coffee or a drink Nice breakfast with good fruit juice and coffee</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Fran</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Very high standard throughout. All facilities including breakfast were first class. Excellent location - 5 mins from Central town station and close to town life including church. Staff are so obliging.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Lyn</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Nice staff, great restaurant and location </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">deb</name>
          <title>Lovely hotel close to everything</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>We loved our stay, clean and comfy , staff were very friendly.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Jo</name>
          <title>Ecellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great location-comfortable beds-very clean-Excellent staff -Huge breakfast-Very reasonable rates </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Helena</name>
          <title>Pleasing</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Nice and reasonably priced hotel in a central location with helpful Staff.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">by A verified traveler</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>We we had a problem the first night as the AC and rig we're not working and this resulted in a sleepness night due to the outside noise from a carnival, as the windows had to be left open to cool the room. They upgraded our room that next day. They had a delicious breakfast though it was served late 730 to 1030 for touring the surrounding. We loved the area and the hotel, as it had old time charm and elegance. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">by A verified traveler </name>
          <title>Stay here</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great location close enough to train for easy day trips to Florence or Pisa, far enough so no noise. Close to everything in Montecatini. Very friendly and accommodating staff.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Robert</name>
          <title>Excellent</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Shame bar and restaurant were not open</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Kira</name>
          <title>Great hotel in wonderful city</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Hotel is centrally located to spas, plazas, restaurants and shops. Hotel restaurant has food that is extremely delicious and fairly priced. Breakfast is a great mix of choices, all outstanding, especially the fresh fruit and the fresh baked goodies.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Charles</name>
          <title>Very Nice Hotel</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The Hotel staff is very friendly and accommodating. The hotel is clean and comfortable and located near the center of the city.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Phillip</name>
          <title>Clean with good location and friendly staff</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>The hotel was clean and deserves a 4 star rating. We had a nice size corner room with 2 large windows. The bathroom was also bigger than normal verses other hotels we've visited in Italy. The location was a 1 minute walk to the main city center. The receptionist (Catia) was very helpful with suggestions for restaurants, spas and other local activities. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">by A verified traveler</name>
          <title>4 star hotel ?</title>
          <num type="rating" value="3">3/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Is this a 4 star hotel - I booked it because it had an excellent rating but this is what we found in our room on arriving - please see photos attached </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mario M</name>
          <title>Good front office staff, the rest terrible.</title>
          <num type="rating" value="2">2/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>No ice machines only at bar you can find some. Internet is slow and unreliable specially if you are going to do work. Night bartender has no customer service skills. Front desk staff are helpfull and try to accomodate guest needs.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Mary</name>
          <title>Short stay, </title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>had a wonderful few days in Montecatini and the hotel was very convenient to all amenities,no problem with parking our car ,but purchase parking ticket from hotel</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Nicole</name>
          <title>Nothing great about it, but a good 3-Star hotel</title>
          <num type="rating" value="5">5/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>Great location. Nice breakfast. Parking is not free, but the day pass is reasonable as long as you can find a parking space near by. The hotel staff are OK, nothing good or bad to say about them. My room was clean, but a bit dated. I used the stairs to go up/down from my room and I noticed that they don't clean them that much. I just thought that the 4-Star rating was a bit too generous for this hotel. A good 3-Star hotel.</p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
    <text>
      <front>
        <head>
          <name type="author">Regina and Hugo</name>
          <title>Hotel staff helpful, excellent cleaning staff, but</title>
          <num type="rating" value="4">4/5</num>
        </head>
      </front>
      <body>
        <div>
          <p>We generally had a positive stay here and housekeeping staff and front desk people were pleasant and helpful. The restaurant was not particularly noteworthy even though it is stated as fine dining. The hotel obviously has no interest in running its bar which is supposed to be open at 5 for cocktail hour. Whenever we wanted to get served there, someone at the front desk had to be asked to have someone at the bar. We then waited for someone to come from the restaurant, who seemed put out to be asked. Often they couldn't make a cocktail and left immediately after waiting on us. We have stayed in hotels in the same city whose bar area was staffed and patronized better. They should just close their bar because no effort is made to operate it. </p>
        </div>
      </body>
    </text>
  </TEI>
</teiCorpus>
